<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Debian on Spaghetti Code with Beer</title><link>https://nagimov.me/tags/debian/</link><description>Recent content in Debian on Spaghetti Code with Beer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 16:32:01 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nagimov.me/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple Recovery of LUKS-encrypted Partitions</title><link>https://nagimov.me/post/simple-recovery-of-luks-encrypted-partitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 16:32:01 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nagimov.me/post/simple-recovery-of-luks-encrypted-partitions/</guid><description>LUKS encryption, while convenient, can become a major pain when the drive gets corrupted. Many things can lead to it:
accidental wipe/format of the boot partition accidental dd to a wrong drive (sure, you pressed ^C right away but your grub is gone, sorry) exceedingly &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; utilities overwriting MBR or re-initializing encrypted partitions drive/memory failures (power outage, random bit flip, etc.) There are plenty of manuals on how to restore an accidentally wiped boot partition.</description></item><item><title>Running Docker on 32-bit Hosts</title><link>https://nagimov.me/post/running-docker-on-32-bit-hosts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:42:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nagimov.me/post/running-docker-on-32-bit-hosts/</guid><description>Docker is known to not to support 32-bit hosts. As per debian installation instructions: Docker CE is supported on x86_64 (or amd64), armhf, and arm64 architectures. 32-bit hosts are unlikely to become supported either &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s bring docker on 32-bit&amp;rdquo; issue was closed and locked back in 2014.
Nothing fundamentally prevents docker (including latest version of docker CE) from running on 32-bit platforms. I am currently running a slightly outdated version 18.</description></item><item><title>alsa-utils' arecord bug: lots of *.wav files, ignoring --duration parameter</title><link>https://nagimov.me/post/alsa-utils-arecord-bug-lots-of-.wav-files-ignoring-duration-parameter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 20:56:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nagimov.me/post/alsa-utils-arecord-bug-lots-of-.wav-files-ignoring-duration-parameter/</guid><description>I ran into a rather funny bug recently &amp;ndash; when recording audio on an RPi with Raspbian Jessie via an external USB sound card, arecord doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop recording after a period of time specified by --duration flag, but keeps running and filling files *-01.wav, *-02.wav, etc. with garbage data. Googling doesn&amp;rsquo;t return a solution, except an obvious one to killall -KILL arecord. USB microphones are also affected.
Since I have another RPi running Wheezy and showing no symptoms of the bug (and being free of systemd malware ;), the bug is likely in arecord itself.</description></item></channel></rss>